Guide to the Samuel L. C. Lee Papers, 1954-1964
Department of Special Collections
Samuel L. C. Lee Papers,
1954-1964
Special Collections M0338
Lee, Samuel L. C., 1878-1964.
4 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Robert L. Levin, 1979.
Biographical Note
Lee, Samuel L.C. (Samuel Cohn) Papers and Plays
4 Boxes app. 4 linear ft.
Collection # 338
1878 Born Samuel Cohn in Ennis, Texas, a suburb of Dallas.
1897 Graduated from Texas A&M with a B.S. in Civil Engineering
1898-1927: worked for the railroads as a civil engineer worked in a lawyer's office studied for, and passed the Texas Bar Exam. worked for his father's retail business travelled around the country conducting liquidation sales
1905 Moved to San Francisco, CA.
1913 Secured a 99 year lease on the Horace Wood property in Indianapolis and started the Circle Theatre with his uncle, Morris Cohn
1928-1942: Owned the Christmas card concession at Livingston's Department Store, Grant and Geary, San Francisco
1942 Retired from work
1943-ca. 1962: Wrote plays while living in San Francisco
ca. 1964 Died
Scope and Content
Collection includes correspondence, typescript plays in various degrees of completion and form, and miscellaneous music and verse.
Container List
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Outgoing Correspondence, 1962-64 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Outgoing Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Incoming Correspondence, A-G (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Incoming Correspondence, H-K (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Incoming Correspondence, L-M (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Incoming Correspondence, N-Z (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 14)
- A Bench in the Park, typed, complete (Box 2, Folder 1)
- A Bench in the Park, typed, complete (Box 2, Folder 2)
- A Bench in the Park, typed, complete (Box 2, Folder 3)
- A Bench in the Park, typed, complete (Box 2, Folder 4)
- A Bench in the Park, typed, complete (Box 2, Folder 5)
- A Bench in the Park, carbon, complete (Box 2, Folder 6)
- A Bench in the Park, carbon, complete (Box 2, Folder 7)
- A Bench in the Park, carbon, complete (Box 2, Folder 8)
- A Bench in the Park, xerox, complete (Box 2, Folder 9)
- A Bench in the Park, xerox, complete (Box 2, Folder 10)
- A Bench in the Park, xerox, complete (Box 2, Folder 11)
- A Bench in the Park, misc. pages (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Half a Day With Tessie, typed, complete (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Half a Day With Tessie, typed, complete (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Half a Day With Tessie, xerox, complete (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Half a Day With Tessie, typed, incomplete (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Half a Day With Tessie, xerox, incomplete (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Half a Day With Tessie, carbon, incomplete (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Half a Day With Tessie, misc. pages (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Half a Day With Tessie, misc. pages (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Half a Day With Tessie, misc. pages (Box 2, Folder 21)
- My Heart Tells a Story, carbon, complete (Box 3, Folder 1)
- My Heart Tells a Story, xerox, incomplete (Box 3, Folder 2)
- My Heart Tells a Story, carbon, incomplete (Box 3, Folder 3)
- My Heart Tells a Story, misc. pages (Box 3, Folder 4)
- My Heart Tells a Story, misc. pages (Box 3, Folder 5)
- My Heart Tells a Story, misc. pages (Box 3, Folder 6)
- My Heart Tells a Story, misc. pages (Box 3, Folder 7)
- My Heart Tells a Story, misc. pages (Box 3, Folder 8)
- My Heart Tells a Story, misc. pages (Box 3, Folder 9)
- He, She, and It typed, complete (Box 3, Folder 10)
- He, She, and It typed, complete (Box 3, Folder 11)
- He, She, and It carbon, complete (Box 3, Folder 12)
- He, She, and It misc. pages (Box 3, Folder 13)
- He, She, and It signs on pasteboard (Box 3, Folder 14)
- A Royal Flush typed, complete (Box 4, Folder 1)
- A Royal Flush xerox, incomplete (Box 4, Folder 2)
- A Royal Flush typed, incomplete (Box 4, Folder 3)
- A Royal Flush typed, incomplete (Box 4, Folder 4)
- A Royal Flush misc. pages (Box 4, Folder 5)
- A Royal Flush misc. pages (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Sequel to `A Roman Holiday' typed, complete (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Sequel to `A Roman Holiday' cc& typed, incomplete (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Sequel to `A Roman Holiday' misc. pages (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Sing and Dance With Me typed, complete, signed (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Sing and Dance With Me manuscript, incomplete (to p.7) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Sing and Dance With Me carbon, incomplete (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Sing and Dance With Me typed, incomplete (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Sing and Dance With Me misc. pages (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous Music and Verse (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Signs for A Wagging Tail Never Bites (Box 4)
- 6 unidentified microfilm rolls of Typescript. (Box 5)